Lois Greene Stone Papers
© 2009 University of Connecticut
Lois Greene Stone Papers.
undated,1951-1996
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Stone, Lois Greene.
.5 linear feet.
Lois Greene graduated from the University of Connecticut in 1955. In 1956, she married Gerald E. Stone, M.D. Ms. Stone has published extensively and is well represented in museums and cultural institutions throughout the United States.
MSS19890029
Biography
Lois Greene graduated from the University of Connecticut in 1955. In 1956, she married Gerald E. Stone, M.D. Ms. Stone has published extensively and is well represented in museums and cultural institutions throughout the United States.
Scope and Content
The collection contains personal materials pertaining to Ms. Stone's years at the University of Connecticut, including clippings, scrapbook pages, grades, lecture notes, assignments and correspondence. A few papers written while attending Columbia Teachers College have been included because the thesis of the paper (text or author) is associated with work completed at the University of Connecticut. Artifacts, dance cards, programs, jewelry and similar items have been identified and incorporated into the larger University Memorabilia Collection.
Arrangement
Series I: Papers ( undated, 1951-1996 ) contains personal memorabilia pertaining to Ms. Stone's years as a student at the University of Connecticut.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University's history. See especially, the papers of Robert F. Belden, A. J. Brundage, James R. Case, Fitts Family, Donald and Margaret Gaylord, Albert C. and Ralph D. Gilbert, Charles G. Hall, Lena Hurlburt, Howard Merrill, Lawrence F. Morico, A. J. Pierpont, Phil Samponaro, August Schulze, Randolph and Beatrice Whaples, and Stanley D. Woodmansee. Relevant administrative collections include the University Memorabilia Collection as well as the records of the Alumni Association, Departments, Board of Trustees, President's Office, the Commencement Collection, faculty papers and subject files. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been identified, separated from the personal collection and incorporated into the appropriate general categories within the University Memorabilia Collection:
Artifacts (ashtray, mug).
Dance cards.
Diploma.
Fraternity/Sorority materials.
Jewelry.
Programs.
The LP album Husky Sings has been transferred to the University Audiovisual Collection.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Stone, Lois Greene.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
College students--Connecticut.; Authors, American.; Artists, American.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; School Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Photocopies.; Notes.; Scrap-Books.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials in the collection have been donated by Mrs. Stone in several installments beginning in 1989.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1951-1996
  - Articles, 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, undated, 1951-1993 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Class related work, 1951-1955
    - Art and Life in America, undated (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Art in the Western World--Parthenon, undated, circa 1955 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - College paper, 1952 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Education 359, undated (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - English class notes, undated, 1955 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - English 117, undated (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - English 205, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Home Economics 142, undated (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Marriage and the Family (Sociology), undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - Notes on Hawthorne and The Scarlet Letter, undated (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Notes on Keats' "Ode to a Nightingale", undated (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Sociology 232 (Culture and Religion), undated (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Student teaching materials, Windham High School, Willimantic, Connecticut, 1955 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Grades, 1951-1955 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Memorabilia (personal), undated, 1951 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook pages, undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)